Nathan Fordyce

Dunfermline, Scotland +44 7810 048867 nathanfordyce06@gmail.com nathanfordyce.wixsite.com/portfolio

STATEMENT

Recent graduate who is seeking an opportunity to break into the software industry. I am a confident, highly motivated and focused individual who has an energetic 'can do' attitude. I enjoy taking on responsibility and actively seeking out opportunities for self-development. I enthusiastically embrace and thrive on new challenges and have a strong desire to achieve success as part of a team and as a developer.

I have been exposed to the software development environment for over 5 years through both academic and personal projects, allowing me to gain a strong working understanding of what is required to make a project a success. Coming from a games development background, I have gained great experience and confidence programming in C++, designing and developing a range of applications from real-time 3D graphics applications to working game prototypes. Mathematics and Physics were core modules during my four-year degree which taught me a variety of skills including vectors, matrices and linear algebra. These skills were then used in a variety of individual and team projects which I developed in university and through game jams in my leisure time. These combined skills have helped me develop and enhance my knowledge of software development, problem solving skills and has enabled me to become an efficient developer.

Automation in the testing and evaluation of any development project is vital. For my university dissertation, I explored automation and artificial intelligence through developing a model capable of learning complex game mechanics such as movement and accurate shooting through two different hardware inputs. This model was implemented to determine the feasibility of using deep reinforcement learning techniques in a games testing stage. This model also allowed me to automatically assess the in-balance between controller and keyboard/mouse players within the developed environment. This was a great insight into exploring the capabilities of automation/artificial intelligence.

SKILLSET

Programming Languages: C++, C#

Other: Source Control (Git), Change Management (Jira).

EDUCATION

Abertay University: BSc Computer Games

Technology (2:1).

Woodmill High School: AABBC

EMPLOYMENT

Amazon - Warehouse Associate

JULY 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

NOVEMBER 2023 - PRESENT

- Working in the customer returns department, where I was responsible for inspecting returned products to determine their condition for resale.
- Working to strict targets to efficiently meet the demand of the business.

The Sweet Chestnut - Kitchen Assistant

MAY 2019 - AUGUST 2019

 Assisting chefs to ensure a great service. Involved in all elements of the kitchen; food preparation, pot washing and shutdown of the kitchen to industry standard.

Achievements

Duke of Edinburgh Bronze Award – This was achieved during my time with the Explorers, having been a member of this organisation since 5 years old until I went to university. To gain this award, I did voluntary work at my church, where I helped organise the annual Holiday Club for the children within the community. I was a member of a local parkour club which helped me keep fit and meet a variety of new people who shared the same interests that I did. The final part of the award was the expedition where I worked with a team to navigate our way between two points using only a map and great teamwork, this included a night under canvas.

Woodmill High School Prefect – After a rigorous selection process, I was successful in becoming a Prefect. In this position, I had a responsibility to act as a role model for other students within the school. I carried out a number of duties, including the safety and well-being of the younger students of the school, assisting teachers with classes and helping out at school events such as parents' evenings.